TheChaosLegion
I want to shine on you, and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect, I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time, and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day, I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
～♪
（兵士たち）えいっ！
It's still here!
（バルサ）まだいるぞ！
チャグム！
Chagum?
Chagum!
チャグム！
Episode 24
The Last Hope
What happened to Chagum?
チャグムに何が起きたんだ
（タンダ）バルサ！ 俺も行く！
Balsa!
I'm coming with you!
（バルサ）来な！
Come on then!
（兵士たちのざわめき）
（シュガ）落ち着け！ 落ち着け！
Calm yourselves!
Remain calm!
Regroup into your teams!
各班ごとに陣形を整えよ
Squads one and two,
accompany me in pursuit of the prince...
１班と２班は
私とともに皇子を追う
Hold on there.
（トロガイ）待たんかい！
Don't be so hasty!
慌てるんじゃないよ
If this place is the land of feasting,
the boy will come back eventually.
ここが宴(うたげ)の地だとしたら―
あの小僧は
いずれ ここに戻ってくる
After all, the egg is supposed
to hatch at dawn tomorrow.
卵がかえるのは
あすの明け方のはずだからね
（シュガ）しかし…
Perhaps, but...
追跡は あいつらに任せておきな
Leave the pursuit to that bunch.
今からでは 到底 追いつけない
You'll never be able
to catch up with them.
What the two of us ought to be
doing is exchanging information.
むしろ 我々がやるべきは
互いの知識の共有
違うか？
Am I right?
Yes...yes, of course.
そう… ですね
そうかもしれない
Perhaps you're right.
Men! Set up bonfires
along the pond's periphery!
皆の者
池の周囲に かがり火をたけ！
We mustn't allow the Rarunga to
attack again when the prince returns!
皇子が戻ったとき―
再び ラルンガの襲撃を
許すわけにはいかん！
Make your preparations at once!
急ぎ 支度をするのだ！
Yes, sir!
Mistress Torogai, the epitaphs
hidden beneath the palace...
（シュガ）トロガイ師―
以前 トウミで
あなたに言われたとおり―
...say much the same thing
that you told us in Toumi village.
宮に眠る碑文にも
“精霊の守り人は―”
“卵食いに引き裂かれる定めである”と
記されていました
It says the guardian of the spirit
will be ripped apart by the egg-eater.
ただ 幸い―
However, we had
the good fortune...
...to learn that Rarunga
could be kept at bay with fire.
火によってラルンガを
退けられるということは分かった
（トロガイ）ふむ… その記述
具体的には どう書かれておった？
Could you tell me
exactly what it said?
On this day 200 years ago,
our founding father used fire...
（シュガ）200年前のこの日―
“シグル”という名の
ヤクーの子供を―
我らの聖祖が火を用いることで
一度は助けたとありました
...to rescue a Yakoo child
named Sigul from the Rarunga.
However, the egg exists
between Nayug and Sagu...
ですが 精霊の卵は―
子供の体の中ではなく
ナユグとサグのはざまにあり―
...not within the child itself.
ニュンガ･ロ･チャガ自身には―
Apparently, the Nyunga Ro Chaga has
no means to deliver the egg himself.
卵を産み落とす手段が
備わっていなかったというのです
As I thought, the only way for the egg
to come out is if it's eaten by a Rarunga?
やはり 卵はラルンガに食われねば
生まれることができんのか
Master Star Reader
Nanai seems to...
ナナイ大聖導師(だいせいどうし)は―
...have observed the
events in minute detail.
そのときの出来事を
つぶさに観察しておられたようで―
同行していたヤクーの呪術師と―
He and a Yakooan magic weaver
who had accompanied them...
...tried desperately
to extract the egg.
なんとか
卵を取り出そうとしていたようです
And then, just when their spell
was on the verge of success...
そして もう少しで
その呪術がうまくいくという刹那―
再びナユグから舞い戻ったラルンガに
子供が引き裂かれてしまった
...the child was torn
apart by a Rarunga...
...which had come
once again from Nayug.
What became of
the egg after that?
（トロガイ）
で その後 卵はどうなった？
Moments after the Rarunga tore
the child apart and swallowed it...
子供を引き裂き
飲み込んだラルンガの口から―
...they witnessed an orb glowing
with a blue light shoot from its mouth.
しばらくして青く光る玉が
吐き出されるのが確認されたそうです
（トロガイ）ほう
After that, something called
a "nahjil" carried it away.
その後 ナージルなるものが
それを運び去ったというのですが―
この“ナージル”という記述が
我らの言葉になかったのです
However, this term "nahjil"
does not exist in our language.
Do you have any idea
what this nahjil might be?
“ナージル”とは何か
分かりますか？
Yes.
It means a nahji, I expect.
そいつは“ナージ”のことだろう
ヤクーの田植え歌に出てくるあれじゃ
The birds in the
Yakoo rice-planting song.
なるほど
Oh, I see...
Damn it all...
お前さんが持ってきた答えで
すべてが解決するかと思ったが―
I had hoped that the answers you
brought would answer everything...
...but they've left us with more
difficult problems than ever.
難問が次々とやって来るわい
Then you do not know any spells
to extract the egg, either?
では トロガイ師も
卵を取り出す呪術は？
No. I won't have any idea what
I might try until it actually happens.
ああ
そのときになってみんことには―
何がどうなってるのか
皆目 見当もつかん
And even assuming that
I manage to extract the egg...
それに うまく卵を取り出せたとして
ナージが飛んでくるかどうかもな
...who's to say that
a nahji will come to us?
That's true...
確かに
This isn't good...
まいったねえ…
Damn. I can't even
find any footprints.
（バルサ）
くそっ 足跡さえ見つからない
It's possible that Chagum
is moving from tree to tree.
（タンダ）もしかしたら チャグムは
木の上を伝っていったのかも
木の上？
Tree to tree?
ああ バルサも見ただろう
Right. You saw him
do it too, didn't you?
チャグムが
水の上を走っていった姿を
Chagum ran on top of the water.
卵は ああして
自分の身を守りながら―
The egg intends to lead the Rarunga
on a chase until dawn to protect itself.
夜明けまでラルンガを
引き付けるつもりなんだ
That's probably also the reason why
Chagum ate that shigu salua flower.
チャグムが
シグ･サルアの花を食べたのも―
恐らく そのためだ
花の匂いが
ナユグのモノを引き付ける
The scent of flowers
attracts creatures of Nayug.
Also...
それと…
（物音）
You lost sight of the prince too?
（モン）
お前たちも皇子を見失ったのか？
（バルサ）
…ってことは あんたたちも？
Meaning that you didn't
have any luck, either?
No.
（ジン）ラルンガの姿を追ったが
途中で消えてしまった
We chased after the Rarunga,
but it suddenly disappeared.
そして
皇子は お前の言うとおり―
And as you said, Prince Chagum
fled by leaping from tree to tree.
木の上を飛ぶように逃げていった
He moved so quickly that not
even we could keep up with him.
我らでさえ
追いつけぬほどの速さでな
You there. Where do you
believe the prince is headed?
（ユン）お主
皇子は どこに向かったと思う？
よくは分からないけど
青池(あおいけ)が宴の地だとしたら―
I don't know for sure, but if Aoike
really is the land of feasting...
夜明けには
戻ってくるかもしれない
...he might return
by daybreak.
とにかく 今のチャグムは
卵に突き動かされているんだ
At any rate, Chagum is under
the control of the egg right now.
Wandering around the forest
isn't going to accomplish anything.
このまま 森をさまよっても
らちが明かない
（ライ）お頭
いったん 青池に戻りますか？
Commander, should we return
to Aoike for the time being?
We mustn't! Even if His Highness
really is being controlled by the egg...
（ジン）ダメだ！
いくら 卵に操られてるとはいえ―
万が一 皇子が
ラルンガに襲われてしまったら！
...what if he is
attacked by a Rarunga?
I'm also against returning to Aoike.
私も青池に戻るのは反対だね
If that's the land of feasting...
もし あそこが宴の地で―
...and he's running from the Rarunga
until sunrise, why would he do that?
朝を迎えるまで ラルンガから
逃げているんだとして―
なんで そんなことするんだい？
He deliberately fled into the forest.
Don't you think there's a reason?
わざわざ 森に逃げ込んだんだ
それにも
理由があるんじゃないのかい？
確かに
俺も短槍(たんそう)使いの意見に賛成だ
Indeed. I agree with
what the spear-wielder says.
シュガ様の推測では 明け方まで
ラルンガは来ないはずだった
According to Master
Shuga's deductions...
...the Rarunga would
not attack until dawn.
There must have been
some sort of miscalculation.
何か読み違いがあったのだ
となると 自力で
チャグムを捜す他はないね
In which case, our only option
is to locate Chagum ourselves.
So it would seem.
（モン）…のようだな
Where do you intend to go?
（チャグム）お前は
どこに行こうとしているんだ？
You're going to follow that
riverbed farther upstream?
あの川を さらに さかのぼるのか？
The Rarunga will come again...
ラルンガが また来る
（無人の体(てい)）ハッ！
It's a good thing that we
don't have to fight those people.
あいつらと戦うことにならなくて
よかったよ
俺の目からも ヤツらが
どれほどの手だれかは分かる
It's clear even to me
just how skilled they are.
You think so?
そうかい
Spear-wielder.
短槍使い
俺は お前に会ったら―
There's one question I had been
meaning to ask if we ever met again.
どうしても聞いてみたいことが
１つあった
That first time we crossed swords,
our team of four failed to kill you.
初めて剣を交えたとき―
我らは ４人がかりで
お前１人をしとめ損ねた
決して 数の利を
過信していたつもりはないが―
I do not believe we were overly
confident in our superior numbers.
あのとき お前は
なぜ 俺たちを殺さなかった？
Why didn't you kill us that night?
その気になれば
全員を殺せたはずだ
I believe you could have killed
all of us had you wished to.
別に大した理由はないよ
No reason in particular.
I had just agreed to save someone, so
I thought it would defeat the purpose...
ただ
これから人を助けようってときに―
他人の命を奪ってたんじゃ―
...if I killed someone
else in the process.
人助けの意味がないって
思っただけさ
（モン）そうか…
I see.
If it had been because
you were looking down on us...
もし 我らを見下してのことなら―
メンツにかけて
ここで けりをつけようと思ったが
...I had planned to settle the matter
here and now to redeem our honor.
But it would seem we
were outmatched all along.
初めから完敗だったようだ
Soon, when we find ourselves
in a cataclysmic battle...
この先
想像を超える戦いになったとき―
我らは迷わず お前に付き従おう
...we will follow you
without hesitation.
Stop that. You're embarrassing me.
やめな こそばゆいよ
My magic allows me to
see the egg inside the boy.
（トロガイ）わしの呪術で
小僧の中の卵を見ることはできる
However, I've never
been able to touch it.
だが
そいつに触ることはできんかった
Even so, if we can find some other
way to interact with Nayug, maybe I...
それでも 何か別の方法で
ナユグと折り合えば…
あるいは… うーむ…
（馬のいななき）
（兵士たち）どうした？ おっ…
What was that?
What's that commotion?
何事だ？
Master Shuga!
Is Master Shuga here?
（無人の体）シュガ様！
シュガ様はおられますか！
シュガ様
ガカイ様からの言づてがございます
Master Shuga, I have a
message from Master Gakai.
この青池は
宴の地ではございません
Aoike is not the land of feasting!
宴の地“サアナン”は こことは
まったく別の場所でございます
Saanan, the land of feasting,
is located somewhere else entirely!
What? What do you mean?
何だと？ どういうことだ！
He says that Saanan's precise
location is recorded on these tablets.
（無人の体）
ここに お持ちした石板に―
サアナンの詳しい場所が
書き記されているそうです
（トロガイ）
ここが宴の地ではないとすると―
If this isn't the land of feasting,
we're in trouble...
やっかいだね
（シュガ）はい
Indeed.
I'd say that it's about
three bells before dawn.
（トロガイ）夜明けまで
あと三の鐘といったところか
I can't believe it. How could we have
missed something so important?
まさか そのように肝心なところを
読み逃していたとは…
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Incredible!
（シュガ）なんと―
Written here is a scene that is identical
to what we witnessed not long ago.
ここに 先ほど我々が目撃したのと
まったく同じ光景が書き記されています
Two hundred years ago,
another child ate a flower...
200年前も “花を食べた子供が
ラルンガを引き連れ森に消えた”とある
...and disappeared into the forest,
leading the Rarunga after him.
Also, it would seem that in Nayug,
this location is the Rarunga's lair.
それに どうやら ここは―
ナユグにおける
ラルンガの巣のようです
The child ate the flower to get
the Rarunga to follow it, then?
花を食うことで
ラルンガをおびき寄せたのか
Yes.
はい
そして “サアナンは ここより北に
20ナンの土地である”と…
Also, it says that Saanan is some
twenty nan to the north of here.
20ナン？
明け方までにギリギリの距離だね
Twenty nan? We'll be lucky to
cover that distance by daybreak.
I will gather my forces,
and we will leave at once.
すぐに軍勢を率いて
出発しましょう
Right, but first we should tell those
who went on ahead about this.
うむ！ だが その前に―
先に行った連中にも
このことを知らせておきたいね
But we--
（シュガ）ですが…
（トロガイ）慌てるな
But we--
Calm down.
タンダのぼんくらが
くっついていったところに―
Luck is still on our side, since
that nitwit Tanda wouldn't leave her.
まだ 運がありそうだ
If this pond is a location that overlaps
with Nayug, this ought to work.
この池が
ナユグと重なる場所なら―
多分 うまくいくよ
Commander.
（ヒョク）お頭
Seems to be no doubt about it.
（モン）間違いなさそうだな？
（ヒョク）はい
No, sir.
They lead up that riverbed.
（タガ）あの沢へと続いています
地上に下りたとなると―
If he's come back
down to the ground...
また 卵食いを
引き付けるつもりかもしれないね
...he might be planning to
attract the egg-eater again.
（モン）川をさかのぼってみよう
Let's try following the river.
Right.
（トロガイ）プハーッ！
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
All right, it worked...
なんとか うまくいった
ハァ… あとはタンダが
これに気付くのを祈るだけじゃ
Now we have to pray
that Tanda spots it.
If those young pups of yours
have joined forces with Balsa...
お前んところの犬っころたちも―
バルサと行動を共にしていりゃあ
一緒に来るだろうよ
...they'll probably turn up too.
ここの連中よりは
役に立つだろうしな
They'll be a lot more
useful than this bunch here.
It'll be a lucky break for us if
they reach Saanan before we do.
運よく先行して―
サアナンに着いててくれりゃあ
めっけもんだ！
お前 馬に乗れるな？
You know how to ride a horse?
We'll ride on ahead on that.
わしらは あれで先に行こう
兵には
あとからついてくるように言え
Tell your troops to follow after us.
卵がかえるときを
逃すわけにはいかないからね
We can't let that
egg hatch without us!
はい
Right!
誰だ？
Who said that?
Hey, Balsa!
おーい バルサ！
ちょっと来てくれ！
Come look at this!
Did he find something?
（モン）何か見つけたのか？
Let's go check it out.
行ってみよう
What's the matter?
Did you find something?
どうした？ 何があった
誰かが俺を呼んでいるんだ
Someone is calling me.
...Tanda...
Y-Yes, that's right.
My name is Tanda.
あ… ああ
“タンダ”ってのは俺だけど？
...Torogai...
...Chagum...
The land of feasting is
twenty nan to the north.
“宴の地は北に20ナン
チャグムも そこに向かった”
Chagum is headed there too.
Is that all?
それで終わりか？
一体 何のまねだい！
What in the world are you doing?
I just got a message
from the mistress.
師匠から伝言が届いた
チャグムの行き先が分かったぞ
I know where Chagum is headed.
チャグムは―
Chagum is headed for
a place called Saanan...
“サアナン”と呼ばれる
青弓(あおゆみ)の水源に向かっている
...one of the Aoyumi's headwaters.
Apparently, that's the
real land of feasting.
どうやら そこが本当の宴の地らしい
Your hunch was right, Balsa.
バルサの読みが当たったよ
となると 猶予は夜明け前
Which means we have
to reach it before dawn!
It's less than three bells to sunrise!
（ジン）
夜明けまで あと三の鐘もないぞ！
They're following
on our heels, right?
あいつらは ちゃんと
ついてきてるんだろうね？
Yes. They are an elite,
handpicked force.
はい
彼らは えりすぐりの精鋭部隊
必ずや 追いついてくれるはず
I am certain that they
will catch up with us.
If we get there,
and it's just us two...
万が一
わしらだけだった場合には…
考えたくはありませんが―
Certainly not an ideal scenario...
そうなったとしても 私は皇子を
なんとしても守ります
...but if that should be the case,
I shall protect the prince myself!
Look at this.
これは…
Yes, it's Chagum's.
ああ チャグムのだ
It hasn't been long since
he passed through here.
まだ そんなに
時間は たってないようだね
Out of the way!
どいてな！
It's those two
creatures from before.
さっきの２匹だ
皇子を捜しているのか？
Are they looking for the prince?
Looks that way.
そうらしいね
だが 昼間より
姿は はっきり見えるぞ
They're much more visible than
they were this afternoon, though.
Did they catch his scent?
匂いを嗅ぎつけたか？
見えるのに なぜ当たらない！
We can see them...
why can't we hit them?
Damn!
（ゼン）くそっ！
It's no use! It won't work unless the
Rarunga is trying to interact with Sagu!
ダメだ！ ラルンガが
サグに干渉しようとしたときでないと…
（バルサ）タンダ！
Tanda!
タンダ！
（モン）ええい！
What did you do?
How could you touch it?
あんた
一体 何をどうしたんだい？
These.
これさ
ラルンガが青池に現れたときに―
When the Rarunga
appeared at Aoike...
こいつの根っこや葉っぱだけには
干渉していたんだ
...the only things it affected were the
roots and blossoms of these flowers.
それで もしやと思って
持ってきたんだけど―
I thought I should bring
some along just in case.
Looks like it was the right call.
どうやら 正解だったみたいだ
チャグムと同じように
こいつを食べれば―
If we eat these like Chagum did,
we'll be able to touch the Rarunga too.
ラルンガに触れることができる
その代わり こっちも ヤツらに
殺される危険は生まれるけど
The downside is that we'll also be
at risk of being killed by those things.
You're hurt!
（バルサ）お前！
Balsa, these flowers
are our last hope.
バルサ
この花が俺たちの最後の希望だ
Can you use these
to save Chagum?
これでチャグムを救えるか？
Yes.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were, at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong." I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in, I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell my dear one, "Thank you."
At the top of my lungs, again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes, human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence of the one that I hold dear.
～♪
Next Time
After the passage of a hundred
years, the promised day dawns.
Saanan is a place of celebration
where living things go to kindle new life.
Next time, "Celebration."
Episode 25
Celebration
Father, child, and mother
will celebrate together there.